（カンクロウ）あんたと
また戦えるなんて→
Fate deemed that I would
fight you again.
これは　運命じゃん。
あのときの借りを
返さなくちゃな。
I owe you one for last time.
（サソリ）俺の傀儡か。
My own puppet, huh…
That body is worthless to me now.
今となれば
その体もくだらねえ。
今の俺は　まさに
朽ちることのない→
Because now, I'm finally a real doll
that will never rot away!
本物の人形そのもの。
かつて望んだ体だ。
This is the body that
I had always wished for!
（シン）逃げろ。
Run…
Captain!
The guy from the Foundation…
隊長！　あの　根の者→
腹の中に　また　あの粘土だ！
He's got that clay
inside his belly!
デイダラの起爆粘土は
雷遁に弱いと聞いたことがある。
I once heard that
Deidara's detonating clay
is weak against
the Lightning Style.
（オモイ）少しなら　俺が…。
I still have a little…
イッタン　負傷者とキリを　岩で囲め！
Take Kiri and the injured
behind that rock!
キリは　回復に専念しろ！　いいか！
Kiri, focus only on healing them!
《デイダラ：遅い！　渇！！》
Too slow!
《今だ！》
Now!
Secret Black Technique! Salamander!
黒秘技　山椒魚！
兄さ～ん！！
Brother!
Sai and Shin
An explosion?!
（中吉）爆発？
とにかく増援…　敵　潰す。
In any case, our reinforcements
will crush the enemy.
Zaji! What's happening out there?!
ザジ　外は？
大丈夫っす。
It's okay.
I can still read their chakra.
チャクラは感知できてる。
みんな生きてる！
Everyone is alive!
Owww…
イテテ…。
命拾いしたぜ。
We're lucky to be alive.
サイ！
Sai!
The Salamander, eh…
（サソリ）山椒魚か。
（デイダラ）隠しておいた
防御用の傀儡で→
So he surrounded the bomb with
a defensive puppet he had hidden.
爆弾を囲うとは。
Because of that, the blast didn't
have much force, hmm.
おかげで　爆破威力は
イマイチだったな。　うん。
爆弾だと…。
You called him…a bomb…?
うん？　何か文句でもあんのか！
You're gonna complain about that?
You're trash.
You can never be Sasuke.
サスケの後釜にもなれねえ
おめえみてえな　カスが→
弱えくせに
でしゃばるんじゃねえ！
So shut the hell up, weakling!
魂が　この世に縛られてるかぎり
何度でも復活できる！
As long as his soul
clings to this world,
I can revive him as much as I want.
また　爆弾にしてやるよ！
I'll turn him into another bomb!
ハハハハハハ！
シン兄さん…。
Brother…Shin…
俺は　お前を傷つけたくはない。
I…
don't want to hurt you.
死んで　もう　根から
解き放たれたのに。
I died…
and was liberated from
the Foundation.
感情を殺す鍛錬とシステム。
I've heard about the Foundation
of the Hidden Leaf.
幼い頃から生活を共にさせ→
You're raised together from
the time you are young,
兄弟のように育ててから
最後に殺し合いをさせる。
like siblings…
Then in the end,
they pit you against one another
in a death match.
木ノ葉の根の掟。
It is a training system designed
to destroy your emotions.
心をなくせば　迷いはない。
Where there is no feeling,
there is no doubt.
それが　本当の強い忍だ。
That makes
a truly powerful shinobi.
根のお前は　俺に近い。
Deep down, you are just like me.
いっぱしに絵なんか描いて
芸術家　気取ってんな！
Don't act like an artist just
because you can draw a little!
Art is an explosion!
芸術は爆発だ！
さて　もう一発　派手にいくか。
I think it's time for
another big blast!
やってみろ！！
Just try it!
((サイ：兄さんに
見せたい絵があるんだ。
I have a drawing
I want to show you, Brother.
へぇ　どれ？
Really? Let's see it.
何だよ？
What is it?
I'm not finished yet…
まだ　完成してないから…。
(もう少し　待って))
so can you wait a little longer?
（デイダラ）ぐあっ！
黒秘技…。
Secret Black Technique…
クソッ…　こんなことなら
さっさと自爆すんだったぜ！
Damn! I should have just
detonated myself earlier!
It's so tacky to exhibit one's
ultimate art over and over!
究極芸術を
そう何度も世に出すのは→
だせえと思ってたが
しかたがねえ！　うん！
But I guess I have no choice!
Hmm!
《雷遁！？》
Lightning Style?!
Triple Iron Maiden!
（カンクロウ）機々三発！
ハァ　ハァ…。
よくやった　オモイ！
Nice job, Omoi!
I'll use my Puppet Jutsu
and keep these two tied up!
ここからは　俺がずっと
こいつら２人を→
傀儡の術で縛り続ける！
Do something about Sai's brother!
サイの兄を　何とかしてくれ！
おう！
Right!
わかってた…　根にいるとき→
I knew that if I remained
in the Foundation,
兄さんと戦わなきゃ
ならなくなるってこと…。
I would have to face you in battle.
あのとき…
つけられなかった決着を…。
So let's settle now what
we couldn't back then.
((あれは　俺のクナイだ。
俺の勝ちだな。
That's my kunai. I guess I win.
きっと　空中でぶつかって
弾き飛ばされたんだ。
I'll bet it collided mid-air
and was knocked off course.
運がないな…。
I have no luck…
運も　実力のうちだ。
Luck is a skill too.
It's decided.
You're on meal duty today.
今日の飯当番は　お前で決まりな。
ちぇっ…。
大丈夫？
来るな！
Are you all right?
Stay away!
なんでもない…。
It's nothing.
そう…　なら　いいんだけど…。
Okay…then it's okay.
♪～
ねえ…。
ん？
Hey…
僕らが　ここに来て
どのくらい　経つのかな？
How long has it been
since we came here?
なんで？
Why?
I was just wondering if
we're going to keep on living here.
僕ら　ずっと
ここで暮らすのかなと思って…。
なんか　もう
シン兄さんと　ダンゾウ様以外とは→
You and Lord Danzo are
the only ones I see.
誰とも会わないから。
So I'm starting to
lose track of time.
日にちの感覚も
なくなってきたよ。
でも　僕はそれでいいけど。
Not that it matters to me.
いつまでも　こうやって→
I want to stay here forever
with you, Brother Shin.
シン兄さんと２人で
暮らしていたい。
そうだ…。
That's right.
なに　これ？
What is this?
開けてみろよ。
Open it.
これって…　スケッチブック！
あぁ。
It's…a sketchbook.
Yeah.
前から欲しがってたろ。
You've wanted one for a long time.
この前　街におりたときに
買っておいたんだ。
I bought it the last time
I went into town.
ありがとう　兄さん！
Thank you, Brother!
決めた。
I know. I'm going to draw pictures
of you and me in here.
これに　僕たちのことを描く。
えっ？
Huh?
僕と　シン兄さんの物語を
絵本にしようと思うんだ。
It'll be a picture book that tells
about you and me.
そうか　できたら見せてくれよ。
男と男の約束。
Okay.
Show it to me when it's finished.
Promise me, man to man.
I'm not kidding!
絶対だからな！
うん！
Uh-huh!
なんて言ったんですか　ダンゾウ様。
What did you say, Lord Danzo?
（ダンゾウ）これからお前たち２人で
生き残りをかけ→
I'm ordering you two
to fight to the death.
殺し合いをしろと言ったのだ。
そんな…。
That's…
これが　お前たちの最終試験。
This will be your final test.
そして　根の宿命だ。
And it is also your fate,
as ones in the Foundation.
もし　３日以降
お前たち２人が生きていたとき→
And after three days,
if you two are still alive
また　２人して
山をおりようとしたとき→
and attempt to descend
from this mountain…
You will die. Understood?
そのときは　お前たち２人とも
命はないと思え。
無理だ　できない…。
That's impossible…
I can't fight with my own brother.
兄さんと戦うなんて…。
なら…　俺がお前を殺す！
Then…I will kill you!
兄さん！
Brother!
本気なの！？
Are you serious?!
兄さん！
Brother!
You are much too gentle
to make it out alive.
生き残るには　お前は優しすぎる。
兄さん…。
Brother…
だが　生き残るのはお前だ。
But you are the one who will live.
俺は病気だ…。
早く手当てを！
I'm sick.
We must get you treated.
It's useless. I've already
looked into my illness.
無駄だよ。
自分の病気のことくらい調べたさ。
この病気は治らない。
そんな…。
It's incurable.
That's…!
このことは　ダンゾウ様も知らない。
Lord Danzo doesn't know about this.
俺を始末したと
ダンゾウ様に報告するんだ。
Report to him that
you dealt with me.
そ　そんなこと…。
I can't…
俺は　根の最終テストが→
I knew all along that
the final test of the Foundation…
仲間殺しだと知っていた。
is to kill a comrade.
えっ！？
Huh?!
So I didn't tell you that
I was sick until this day.
だから　この日まで→
お前に病気のことを隠しながら→
生きようと思ってた…。
I tried to live with this secret.
お前と刺し違える形で
負けようと…。
So that I could lose to you
in a swordfight.
けど　その体力も
残っちゃいなかった　だせぇ…。
However, I don't even have
enough strength to pull that off.
兄さん…　僕だって→
Brother, I also knew that
I would have to fight.
兄さんと戦わなきゃ
ならなくなるって知っていた…。
けど　兄さんと
戦うなんてできない！
But I never expected it to be you…
そうだったのか…。
Is that so?
心を殺せ！
You must kill your emotions.
でなきゃ　いつかお前は
任務に押しつぶされる。
Otherwise, duty will destroy you.
行け　俺の分まで生きろ。
Now go…
And live my share too.
兄さん…。
Brother…
自分くらい　自分で始末する…。
I'm still capable of
ending my own life.
行け！
Go!
泣くな！
心を殺せって言ってるだろ。
Don't cry! Didn't I tell you
to kill your emotions?!
わかった。
I understand.
♪～
お前の完成した絵→
I wish I could have seen…
your finished drawing.
(見たかったな))
あのときの決着か。
Settle that last match…huh?
大丈夫か　サイ！
サイ　そうか。
Are you all right, Sai?
Sai…
I see, so that's your name now.
それが今のお前の名前…。
だが　そうはならない。
However, it won't happen.
兄さん！
完成したんだな。
Brother…
So you finished it.
やっと見たかった絵が見られた。
I finally got to see the picture
I longed to see…
お前の絵が俺の魂の縛りを
解いてくれたみたいだ。
It's as though…
your drawing has freed
my soul from its bindings.
サイ　お前の名前を
呼んでくれる仲間を→
Sai, these comrades who
call you by your name…
大事にしろよ。
Cherish them.
ありがとう。
Thank you…
What's going on?
どういうことだ。
The strings are slack…
《糸の手ごたえがない》
サソリ　あんたの戦いぶりは
サクラから聞いたよ。
Sasori… Sakura told me
how you fight.
あのとき　チヨバアといた女か。
Back then…
The girl who was with Granny Chiyo.
Cha!
((サクラ：しゃ～んなろ～！
うわ～！
This is a jutsu I personally sealed.
（チヨバア）これは己で禁じた術。
I didn't think I'd ever use it again.
二度とは使うまいと
思っておったが→
But it seems it won't
work out that way.
そうもいかんようじゃ。
はっ！
Now let's put an end to this!
これで幕引きにしようぞ！
♪～
There's so many…
すごい数…。
さすがババアだ　傀儡使いは
使える傀儡の数で→
I'd expect no less from you, Granny.
It's said the number of
puppets they can use
measures the ability of
a puppet master.
その者の能力が
測れると言われるが。
Granny Chiyo's secret
"Number of Fingers."
チヨバアの極意　指の数
噂には聞いたが→
I'd heard rumors about it.
The device you used to
bring down a castle by yourself…
それが城一つを
一人で落としたというカラクリ。
The Secret White Move:
Chikamatsu's 10 Puppets.
白秘技　十機近松の集。
The ten masterpieces by Monzaemon,
傀儡の術
初代操演者モンザエモンの十傑作。
the first puppeteer of
the Puppet Master Jutsu.
It's a great collection of puppets.
たいした傀儡集だ。
だがな。
However…
I used this to bring down a nation…
俺は　これで一国を落とした。
(赤秘技　百機の操演！))
Secret Red Move: Performance
of a Hundred Puppets!
あんたの強さは
そこに魂があったからだ。
The source of your power
lay in your soul.
あんたは　かつて人形になり→
You once turned yourself into a puppet,
魂を消そうとしたが
消しきれなかった。
and tried to erase your soul,
but you couldn't do it.
あんたの作った傀儡にこそ
朽ちることのない魂が宿ってる。
I can feel it inside this puppet
that you made,
where your undying soul dwells inside.
それが　俺には　わかる。
しかし　今の　あんたは生身だが→
But now, you are living flesh,
but that's merely a human shell that
has degenerated into a puppet.
本物の傀儡に成り下がった
ただの人形だ。
あんたは
傀儡を操る　一流の忍だった。
You were a first-rate
shinobi puppet master.
誰かに操られるような
ゲスじゃ　なかったはずだぜ。
Not some lowlife that allows
someone else to manipulate you.
カブトは　確か→
If I'm not mistaken,
you used Kabuto as a spy back then.
あの頃　あんたが使ってた
スパイだったな？
なのに　今じゃ
あんたが　操られるなんて…。
Now, he's the one using you.
It's over when a puppet master
is the one being manipulated!
傀儡使いが　操られちゃ
おしまいじゃん！
あんたにも
あんたを操ってる　カブトにも→
And whether it's you, or Kabuto,
the one who is controlling you…
こっちは　意地でも負けらんねえ。
There's no way I'm gonna lose…
同じサソリを　操ってるなら→
Because I am the ninja puppet master
of the real Sasori puppet!
なおさら　本物を操る
傀儡忍者としてよ！
あんたの技術…
そして　作った傀儡は→
Your techniques and the puppets
you created will never decay.
朽ちることのないもんだ。
そこに宿る魂を受け継ぐ
後世の操演者が　いてこそな！
As long as there are
future puppet masters
to inherit the soul that
resides within them!
それこそ
俺の望んだ　芸術の形か…。
So that is precisely
the true form of art I sought…
ふざけんじゃねえぞ！
Quit joking around!
サソリの旦那！
My man Sasori!
こんなやつらの口車に
乗せられてんじゃねえぞ！　うん！
Don't pay any attention to this jerk, hmm!
芸術は　一瞬の輝き！
Art is a single flash of light!
芸術は　爆発だ！
Art is an explosion!
（デイダラ）聞いてんのか？
サソリの旦那！
Are you listening, Sasori?!
《作った者の魂が　宿るか…。
The soul of the creator
resides within, eh…
確かにな…》
You're right…
カンクロウ。
Kankuro…
なんだ？
What is it?
（サソリ）父と母の傀儡も　お前に託す。
I entrust you with the "Father"
and "Mother" puppets.
そして　お前が死ぬ時は
更に　次の者に託せ。
And when you die,
bestow them upon another…
あの　２体は…。
Those two are…
あぁ…　もちろん　わかってる。
Yeah…of course, I understand.
おい！　サソリの旦那！
Hey! My man Sasori!
♪～
これは　生け贄！
どういうことだ…。
This is a sacrificial victim…
What's going on?
穢土転生は　死ぬことがない術だと
聞いたが…。
I heard that one couldn't die
under the Reanimation Jutsu.
カブトが
術を　解いたんじゃねえかな？
Maybe Kabuto released the jutsu?
出せ　この野郎！
Let me out, you bastard!
どうやら　そうでは　なさそうだな。
It doesn't seem that way.
– Hey, can't you hear me?
– Sasori is gone,
サソリのほうは　いなくなってるが
うるさいのが　まだ　いる。
but the loud one is still here.
完璧に思えた
この　穢土転生とかいう術にも→
We thought the Reanimation Jutsu
had been perfected,
穴が　あったみてえじゃん。
but it seems to have a flaw.
人の気持を　そんな簡単に
縛りきれるもんじゃねえだろ。
It's not that easy to control emotion.
終わったみたいだな。
いや…　これからじゃん。
Looks like it's over.
Nope…this is just the beginning!
サイ　オモイ　ザジ！
すぐに　奇襲へ向かえ！
Sai, Omoi, Zaji!
Head out for immediate ambush.
（３人）オスッ！
– Yes!
– Right!
（マダラ）どうした？
What is it?
（カブト）いや…　なんでもない。
Oh, nothing.
《穢土転生…
まだまだ　未知の部分が多い術だ。
The Reanimation Jutsu…
There are still so many
mysteries behind it.
だが　これで
だいたいの感じは　わかった》
But I have a good idea of
how it works now.
マダラ　君は　戦線へ行ってくれ。
Madara, head out to the battlefront.
僕は　身を隠し　術のため集中する。
I'll hide and focus on the jutsu.
《この女…。
This woman…
アジトに
ここまで　近づいていたのか…。
She had gotten
this close to our hideout.
そして　そのことを知っていたカブト。
And Kabuto was aware of it.
わざと　この女を導いたな…。
So he purposely lured her here?
カブトめ…　ハナから→
That damned Kabuto…
Since the beginning,
こっちと　連合軍の共倒れを
狙う気だろうが　フッ→
he's planned for the Allied Shinobi Force
and us to destroy each other.
そうは　いかんぞ。
But that won't happen
利用するのは　こちらだ》
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。